VICTOR APAEZ | Software Engineer

Brooklyn NY

Email: vic.apaez@gmail.com

Cell: 929-331-1450

LinkedIn Github Portfolio

Software Engineer with experience in Management. Eager to bring forward innovative and creative solutions to improve the way we interact with technology. Proven to be a leader, team player, and reliable worker with three years experience as manager for an E-commerce.

Skills

MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, JSON, HTML, CSS, Github, Git

PROJECTS

League of Legends | FE - Github | BE - Github | Live Demo

With over 117 million users for the game of League of Legends, this web application helps gamers search and build teams with their favorite characters and items.

- Managed a team of 5 developers to create a web application with MongoDb, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js.
- Directed team standup meetings to check on progress and plan code direction.
- Implemented user authentication on the server using jsonwebtoken and bcrypt.
- Built endpoints to sign up, sign out and verify the user on the back end.

Breddit | FE - Github | BE - Github | Chat BE - Github | Live Demo

Inspired by Reddit, this web application is a network of communities where people can share their interests and ideas.

- Collaborated with a team of 9 developers to create Better Reddit using React.js, Django, and Express.js.
- Produced a viable product with over 450 commits in 5 days using feature branch workflow.
- Designed a chat server to establish a WebSocket connection using socket.io.

Trailers App | Github | Live Demo

A Netflix replica, this web application has trailers for top rated, now playing, and current entertainment.

- Engineered a web application for watching trailers using React.js and Styled-components.
- Implemented The Movie DB API to fetch film and tv series data.
- Utilized IFrame Player API to display video trailers using keys fetched by the The Movie DB API.

EMPLOYMENT

General Assembly - Software Engineer Fellow

Sept 2022 – Dec 2022

- Full time fellow in the Software Engineering Immersive program that includes over 400 hours of professional training over 12 weeks. Utilizes hands-on approach to design and build web applications with full CRUD functionality through
- Javascript, React, Express, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, etc.

Rubber Stamp Creation - Manager

Nov 2019 - Sept 2022.

- Researched, hired, and trained new company employees according to the needs of the departments
- Delegate responsibilities to the best-qualified employees and enforce all policies, procedures, standards, specifications, guidelines, training, and cultural values
- Overlooked day-to-day operations, assigned performance goals and ensure their completion

EDUCATION

General Assembly - Software Engineer Immersive

Sept 2022 – Dec 2022

New York City College of Technology - Computer Science: Completed 70 credits.

2014 - 2017